Every bellend online
is trying to teach you how to get rich,
but instead, I'm going
to teach you as a personal trainer how I
would make your first [till ringing] $350
a day. This could get spicy.
And I've said this before, I say it again,
you must master in person first.
And that goes to other niches too,
whether you're a physiotherapist,
whether you're
a psychologist,
whether you're a personal trainer.
So many people today arrive at the online
scene and go, "I want to work online."
And sell what, brother? What is it
that you think you're selling
if you have zero
experience doing the thing
that you want to sell?
Just because you went to the gym
and benched 100 kg does not make you a
personal
trainer. Also, worth noting that there
is a bundle discount in the description to
this video called the PT Starter Kit,
where basically I teach you everything
about
running a PT business,
and I give you a $99 content creation
course, which is, in
essence, free. Now,
I can't say this enough either,
the sessions that you do in
person are some of the least paid sessions
possible, but in years to come, you're
going to look back at them and they
are going to be the accelerators
that allow you
to earn crazy amounts of money.
And out of all the people
that you know that do the
same job as you, you'll earn the most,
and it's because of that.
We look at Adam Sullivan, EBT,
spent 10 years on the gym floor.
Even Joe Wicks got his reps in before
going online.
Kayla Itsines worked in a gym before she
became online.
I did three years,
5,000 hours of one-to-one sessions before
I went
online. And you need
that raw experience for every component of
being a great
online trainer.
So I'm going to say this again.
If you want to be great online,
you need to be great in person first.
Now,
although I've shattered your dreams
and you think you've got to go to the gym,
walk the floor, and talk to strangers,
and do that annoying thing where you go
over
and go, "Hey mate,
can you take your headphones out?"
And they're going to go,
"What? What's that? Oh,
you want to sell me your PT?" No, sorry.
No. Bye." It's soul-destroying,
but you've got to get used to it.
And it may take you three months to fill
your PT diary.
It might take you six months,
but I need you to start doing
that right now, today,
tomorrow. If you're not qualified,
get qualified.
The qualification's dog shit,
but you need to do it so you can get
insured on a gym
floor.
But you need to start posting today.
Not when you're qualified, today.
I need you to do it not
when you've filled your PT books, today.
Because for the first 100 posts online,
you're going to eat shit, and you need to
eat shit because it's one of the most
beautiful parts of the journey.
And some of you are waiting to get good
before you start,
and I'm going to tell you
why that's a big issue.
Let's say in this room,
I've got 100 personal trainers to
my left and 100 personal trainers to my
right.
I say to the group on the left, "Hey guys,
I need you to collectively all come
together and make the most viral piece of
fitness content ever.
I'm going to give you a year to create
this piece of content.
So spend a year researching,
spend a year looking at your competitor
analysis, and
make me that perfect reel.
You've got 100 brains.
You've got 365 days.
Go." To the group on the right, I say,
"Every one of
you, 100 of you,
must make a piece of content every single
day.
Whether it's written,
whether it's a carousel,
whether it's a video, every day you
must put out a piece of content.
There must be no days off,
no repeating the same
video.
New piece of content every day." Out of
those two groups, who comes up with
the biggest outlier, crazy viral reel?
It's going to be the team
that do the volume because they're going
to get so much
feedback from the reels
that do better than expected
and all the ones that do
worse.
There's a term called regression to the
mean.
I need you to do something 100 times
before we can really see how good you
are at
that thing.
Even if it's flicking a coin into a
bucket.
If you miss the bucket wildly,
I can predict the next one's going to be a
lot
closer,
and if you get the coin in the bucket,
I can predict the next one's
probably not going to go in.
And we have the exact same with our
content.
Some will go wildly off to the left,
some will go wildly off to the right.
Some will overperform,
some will underperform.
But every single reel
is a little bit of feedback.
365 pieces of feedback
is so much more than one piece of
feedback. And it is only through
that sheer amount of volume
that something will
educate you in the direction you need to
go to become a good content creator.
I didn't swear in my first 500 pieces of
content.
Then one day,
I probably had one too many cans of White
Monster, and I went on a
rant, and I swore,
and I called everyone fucking cunts.
More engagement than usual.
So I went back to normal.
Then I did another one swearing.
Swearing got me further.
Carried on.
Daniel Priestley taught this to me in a
podcast I did with him last
week. Imagine this is a bell curve.
Traditionally,
income would be split where most people
would earn the average
amount.
Some people would earn a little bit more.
Some people would earn a little bit less.
So potentially,
someone in a more senior role might earn a
little bit more.
But there weren't many people earning the
big bucks, and then there'd be a few
people earning less,
and there weren't too many people not
earning at all.
But this has changed. Sadly,
in the world of online personal training,
this is how
it looks. This is the halfway point,
and this is the top 10th
percentile.
The majority of personal trainers,
easily 9 out of 10,
earn little to nothing.
They make just about enough,
maybe minimum wage, maybe
enough to get by.
But they're still having to be mindful of
their grocery bills.
Their heating bills still stress them out.
Life isn't easy for them.
Then the top 10% earn everything.
Kayla Itsines, sold a business for over
300 million. Adam Sullivan,
making a million a month.
Me, I do okay. Who else is making it rain?
I'm pretty sure Courtney Black's got over
10 million pound in her current account.
But this isn't here to depress you.
It's to bring the reality of this.
So many of you start your journey.
You post on social media.
You grow your following.
You build your email list.
But you're still earning shit money.
You keep going. You keep persevering.
Unfortunately, this
is what I call the valley of death.
This is where most people give up because
they've been going for so long.
Back in the day,
they would have already surpassed the
average amount of money, and
they would be in the high earners.
But in today's age,
they're not there anymore.
But little do they know how close they
are to potentially
earning more. And even
when they hit the 90th percentile,
even when
they've done everything
that they've been told, the content,
the emails, the
marketing, the turning up,
the thousands of hours in person,
people still give up
here.
Then even going from the 90th percentile
to the
92nd, it's only a small increase in money,
still not
noticeable.
Then they reach the 95th percentile.
Now suddenly, they've got more money.
Now they're starting to think about going
on holidays.
Then when they hit the 96th percentile,
they're like, "Holy crap, I can afford
to fly business class now. Wow,
I've now got money left in the bank at the
end of
the month." Then the 98th percentile,
they can hire people,
expand, staff.
Then there's the 99th percentile,
people that are making hundreds of
thousands of dollars a year, maybe even
millions.
So many people don't realize how close
they are to
being in that top percentile,
but only one in 100 people can be in
that top
percentile. The reason
that this feels so hard and so tough
is because the
game has changed.
The allocation of resources is only in the
last few percent. If you do not climb
and work and hustle all your way to there,
you can make it here with nothing,
here with nothing, here with nothing,
here with
nothing.
This isn't just about getting ahead.
Everything I'm teaching you to do in these
videos Is about getting into the top
10%. And if more people understood this,
less people would give up here.
Personal training must have the highest
rate out of any profession I know where
people go, "Oh,
I used to be a personal trainer." Used to
be?
Brother, you get to bang weights at work.
You get to build a gym and expense it.
You get to wear shorts all the time.
You get to help people lose fat,
build muscle, feel better,
get their sex drive
back, and you gave that up.
If people just understood the valley of
death and the
top 10%,
they could have such an easier time
navigating through
the eating shit that
is necessary to grow your business.
Right, back upstairs.
One of the next things that's really
important is that you
steal good ideas.
So you must look at other industries.
Let's say you're an accountant
and you're starting to make accountant
content.
You should look at Damian Talks Money on
YouTube, and you should probably look at
Josh Thomas' account on Instagram.
You should start to look at their setup,
their hooks, how they present themselves,
how their lighting looks, how long
are their videos, which one did best.
On YouTube,
you can quite literally go to someone's
page, click videos, click most
popular,
and you there have in chronological order
all of the best things they've
ever spoken about,
which should give you ideas about what to
talk about.
Whether it's in your niche or not,
there are going to be outliers at play
that you
can just go and steal. Then suddenly,
one of your competitors takes a prop and
goes,
"This board marker represents a year's
worth of fat loss." And you go, "Wow,
that was really easy to understand." So in
your next video, you grab something
else.
"This bottle represents one year of fat
loss." And again, with the feedback
that you get from the video,
did a prop help or did it hinder?
Did asking a question help? Did it hinder?
Did making a statement help?
Did it hinder?
And there's going to be little bits of
success that you can find in
your competitors. Now,
you might be worried about copying them.
And I've got a video at the end of this
video that's going to teach you everything
you need to know about copying someone,
but you're just merely stealing the idea.
And I guarantee the person
that you saw online that
was making a video with a pen
took that idea from someone else
that they saw.
Now this is where working in person with
people and working online comes
together.
If you're stuck for content ideas,
I want you to do this as an exercise.
You're going to get a document out.
You're going to write down your five
favorite clients.
You're going to put their names.
You're going to write their journey,
what they're
struggling with,
and how you plan to overcome it.
So hypothetically speaking, Declan,
give me one of your old clients.
What was their name? Wendy. Okay,
and what was Wendy's struggle?
She did not enjoy lifting regular weights.
And how did you overcome that?
Took her to the park and did calisthenics,
body weight movements. Cool.
So there's a video in there straight away.
I've just been put on the spot.
What if I was to tell you there
was a way for people
that hated going to the gym
that they could resistance train
and get all the benefits they need,
especially in
older populations,
and you could do it from going to the
park? Well, this is Wendy.
I trained her for six months,
and what we did was we swapped the gym for
going to
the park,
and we did something called calisthenics,
which means using body weight
to exercise. All we needed
was a suspension trainer,
some resistance bands, because
most people over-complicate fitness,
and the reality is you just need an
element of
push, pull, and squat. God,
I'm fucking flying. That is in.
It's getting parked now. Woo.
That's a piece of content.
Then you could go to your next client
and do the same.
It is working with real people
that you understand real problems where
you can then
communicate to it, because guess what?
If you communicate Wendy's point online,
you attract other Wendys.
Then you have a Dave.
You talk about Dave's problem,
you attract other Daves.
So we're going to call this the $350 a day
axis.
The reason that I want you to work in
person first is this.
Let's say today is here.
Let's say two years.
Brown is going to represent in-person
personal training.
You can get to $350 a day much faster in
person than you ever can
online. It's seven clients a day.
You could probably, in three months, go
ham, talk to everyone in the gym,
in the facility.
That's why the facility matters.
In a private gym,
you've got no one to prospect,
no one to PT in front of.
Just remember,
if you work in a commercial gym with loads
of people in there,
they've seen you at work,
they're familiar with you,
they know what you look like,
and they know how you act around your
clients.
If you're in a PT-only facility,
although it seems cool and sexy and
nice, getting clients
is going to be way harder.
So you must work in person because you've
seen the valley of death already
before. If you go just online,
you're going to hit
that valley of death still
earning not a lot of money. Blue
is going to represent running an online
business because you need to build your
following, get people familiar with you,
have videos that bomb, have videos
that suck. Online looks more like this.
You need to build your in-person business.
At this point, you can live life.
You can get on with your life.
You can have kids. You can be sensible.
You can be saving. You can go on holiday.
But online is a slow burner.
It takes time. The compounding interest,
similar to saving money in an interest
savings account.
And sometimes it takes you to get to
nearly two years of doing
both at the same time before you can
actually surpass that amount.
It takes time to get to the point
that you can surpass in person.
Then once you get to this inception point,
you can give up in-person training and
go fully online.
But let's not kid yourselves.
You've got to do the work first.
If you've got bills to pay, it
is much easier to do it in person.
Get to that $350 a day in person.
Then you'll be doing a little bit
of online and a little bit in person.
Then as you get to this point
and demand grows for online,
you can start to
transition and go fully online.
Then the earning potential of doing online
can go
forever. But in person,
you're pretty much bottomed out at six
sessions a day,
maybe seven, but you'll burn out.
If you're young, you can get away with it.
This place here is perfect because it's
hybrid.
You're actually doing things with people
in the day, working the first few hours in
the morning, get great ideas for content,
making content that serves your online
clients. Here's the difference, though.
If I train someone in person here,
an hour session is going to take an hour.
But if I have a client who I'm working
with online, brother, I'm going to smash
me a couple cans of No Tonic,
and I'm going to get all my clients done
in two
hours. Then working online,
your hourly rate is
accelerated by your productivity.
That's why you need No Tonic.
Head to notonic.com. Oh, and what's this?
Some Retatrutide.
New video in the making.
Don't you worry about that, Declan.
That's what's in there. Don't you worry.
Oh, here it is.
No, that's not cocaine.
Although I know you would've seen a lot of
that in Vegas.
This is so much of what I do with my
mentorship, with my online coaching,
with my
PT Starter Kit,
is building your expectations.
I could say, "Hey,
have financial freedom in three months."
But you can't get good
at anything in three months.
Have you ever seen anyone that's trained
jujitsu, how
dog shit they are after three months?
This is the reality. This is how it is.
If this sounds too much like hard work,
then fuck off back to your job in
recruitment.
But if you're willing to do this
and dig in, you can have everything.
Keep in mind,
my fitness business didn't pay for that.
My fitness business paid for this.
My fitness business paid for me to travel
the world.
My fitness business paid for me to have a
house.
But it was what I learnt from running a
fitness business
that allowed me to spin up
new businesses like No Tonic to get myself
my first GT3.
It'll take you two years to go fully
online in your first business.
It will not take you
that long once you've done it.
Once you've become proficient with
everything it takes to dominate this
online
world, you can flip it into anything.
That's the exciting part.
Because if you work in a PT gym For 10
years, you've just become
good at coaching people in person.
But when you can understand
and work the online elements of running a
business,
$350 a day is just your start point for
much bigger things.
Right, back to the video upstairs.
Then over time, as you build interest
and you get engagement online on social
media,
you will then start to take people's
contact information, roughly about 20%
of your total audience.
So any of you watching this, question,
do you have 20% of
your audience on your email list? If no,
stop focusing on growing your socials and
start focusing on getting their
information.
If you do have 20%,
probably time to grow the following a bit
more so that
percentage comes down
and we can shift the focus,
like a bulk and a cut between
growing and harvesting.
It's also important to do this because
your brand may
change. Myself,
most email addresses I got
was from fitness and writing books.
I now use it to promote Newtonic
and maybe even this business mentorship
course,
which there's a link to in the
description.
Sean Casey, started in person,
works online,
now has a business called Social
Circle where he helps PTs.
Evidence-Based Training, Adam Sullivan,
got his email
addresses from fitness, sells merchandise,
and soon sell creatine gummies.
Now, that $350. If we imagine
that you charge $50 an hour, which is a
moderate amount to charge.
That's probably, what, £40 in the UK?
That's maybe near 100 bucks in Australia.
You would just need to see seven clients a
day.
And to begin with, that
is long because personal training sessions
are one-on-one
meetings.
It's like being booked out for every
single hour.
And you could be starting your day at 6:00
a.m. and not finishing until 6:00 p.m.
But then as demand increases for your
services,
you manage to block your diary and
who knows? You might start at 6:00 a.m.
and finish at 3:00 p.m.
You might have a lunch break
and two little gaps.
But here is the kicker,
the elephant in the room,
the pain point that most of you
watching this are going to resonate with.
That is not sustainable.
You cannot do seven hours a day,
five days a week forever.
But the good news is you don't have to.
For some of you, a year.
For some of you, five years.
It depends how hard
and aggressive you market
yourselves online,
build an online presence,
and collect data from people.
It is whether or not you try
and stumble over getting the perfect post
or whether
you just start putting out raw volume.
Because $350 a day is $2,450 a week.
To get that online,
you would need 49 clients charging 50
bucks a week, which
again, is on the light end. Now,
me saying that you could earn $350 a day
being remote anywhere in the world to look
after 49 clients.
49 can seem a lot, but it's not.
You could rotate their programs every two
weeks.
So that means you're writing 25 programs a
week.
If you were to spend half an hour writing
each program, you're suddenly down to 12
hours. Working five days a week,
it's just over two hours each day.
Not to mention a little bit of time
communicating.
Again, I'm not the biggest believer
that you need to book in weekly calls with
your
clients for $50.
You're going to have me on WhatsApp,
you're going to ask me any
questions you want, and if anyone
is too high maintenance
and they're feeling to me
like I'm not getting a good deal for $50,
I'm going to boot them and replace them
with someone new.
Because some clients will take no stress,
they'll just get on
with their program and get mad results,
and some people expect the world.
But the more engagement
and more contacts that you have online,
the more you can
curate those 49 people to be the perfect
clients for you.
Low admin, hard workers,
love what they get,
happy to stay with you long
term. Because after a while,
they're not paying you $50 a week for
online coaching,
they're paying you $50 a week for what
they get from it, which is that they're
hitting all their workouts.
And for some of them,
if you put them on a three-day
split,
they're paying you less than 20 bucks a
workout, which is phenomenally
cheaper than working with a coach in
person.
They're paying you $50 a week,
so they adhere to their dietary protocols.
They're paying you the money and they go,
"Well, I best not eat that crap because
I'm spending so much money with my
trainer." $350 a day is not that far away.
Now,
the amount of time you want to spend
getting there depends on how hard you
want to work, you want to hustle,
how many posts you want to put out a day.
And I guarantee this,
if you post twice as much as your
competitor, you'll get
there in half the time.
You need a good offer, a good program,
a big email list,
and a strong brand online, and it
is incredibly possible to get there.
Now, here's the really exciting bit.
Personal training is an incredibly fucking
hard profession.
Once you get from zero to $350 a day,
the rest is easy because
the skills you learned in content
creation, email marketing,
building landing
pages, creating good offers,
once you learn that in the trenches,
training at
altitude, doing personal training,
spinning up new things,
maybe an electrolyte
business, maybe a new drink, a product,
a supplement, a sleep supplement, whatever
it is,
will be easy in comparison to building a
personal training business.
So it's imperative
that you start putting out content today.
You post every single day
and you wait for the outliers to recruit.
Nothing beats raw,
sheer volume in this game.
Everyone's trying to sell you a secret
system or a method.
I've done over 4,500 Instagram posts.
That is why I'm here today doing this
video,
because I've learnt more from videos
bombing, eating shit,
than most of my competitors combined.
And that's why my fitness business has
done over seven figures every year for
seven
years. And truth be told,
I probably only do three hours every 12
weeks work to
keep that alive. But anyway,
that PT starter kit is phenomenal value.
There's a link in the description.
It's got everything you need.
It's got short-form content mastery
involved.
Check it out,
and if you want to work with me,
there's going to be a link there
too. Now before, for some of you
that thought, "Oh,
isn't it bad to steal people's
ideas and rip them off
and use them as your own?" I get that,
but if you watch this
video right here,
I explain exactly how I stole someone's
idea that's not even in
the same niche as me,
and I made over $12,000 in the first day I
implemented it.
Thanks for watching.